Guide to the Samuel B. Bassett Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Samuel B. Bassett papers
1926-1965
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1792
1792-001
Bassett, Samuel B.,$d1896-1971
3' linear
Legal case files of a lawyer in Seattle, Washington
Bassett was a Seattle plaintiffs lawyer who practiced with George Vandeveer from 1924-1942 and represented the Joint Council of Teamsters, No. 28 and various Teamster locals.
Legal case files (bulk), 1926/27, ca. 1948-1965; incoming letters, 1953, 1963.
Accession includes a sample of legal records showing early and distinctive cases, including a wire tapping case, an Indian fishing rights case, a case involving dismissal of a University of Washington basketball coach, and cases involving Seattle labor unions and labor leaders, including Frank Brewster.
Access restricted: For terms of access, contact Special Collections for details.
Donated by Bassett, Donaldson & Hafer, 1/1/1972.
The visual materials that form part of this collection are described and indexed in
A Guide to the
.
Inventory/container list available in Special Collections.
Bassett, Samuel B.,$d1896-1971$vArchives; Brewster, Frank W.$vTrials, litigation, etc.; Vanderveer, George F.; Finley, Robert C.; Grayson, John; Beck, David (Dave) Daniel; Green, Charles S.$vTrials, litigation, etc.; Karlstrom, Lena$vTrials, litigation, etc.; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); City of Hope.; Makah Tribal Council (Neah Bay, Wash.); International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America.$bLocal 174; International Stevedoring Co.$vTrials, litigation, etc.; Indians of North America$xFishing$xLaw and legislation; Basketball coaches$xDismissal of$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Wiretapping$xLaw and legislation
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Laws and Legislation; Washington (State); Seattle
- ORGANIZATIONAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS, 1928-1971; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1, 4/51)
  - Box Copy of Inventory
  - Clipping of Samuel Bassett obituary and pencil sketch art, labeled 'Sam', Undated, 1971 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Thesis (Admissibility of Evidence Obtained by Wire-Tapping - by Samuel Bassett), 1928 (Box-folder 4/51)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1927-1965; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/2, 4/1-4/34)
  - Incoming letters - General, 1953-1963 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Incoming Letters - A, 1934-1952 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Incoming Letters - B, 1928-1952 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Incoming Letters - Blanken, David L., 1936-1939 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Incoming Letters - C, 1931-1954 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Incoming Letters - D, 1931-1952 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Incoming Letters - Delta Theta Phi, 1943-1952 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Incoming Letters - E, 1934 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Incoming Letters - F, 1933-1952 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Incoming Letters - Foster, Harry Ellsworth, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Incoming Letters - G, 1937-1951 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Incoming Letters - Green, B. A., 1930-1951 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Incoming Letters - H, 1934-1954 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Incoming Letters - Hartford Accident and Indemnity Co., 1935-1950 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Incoming Letters - I, 1942 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Incoming Letters - J, 1928-1948 (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Incoming Letters - K, 1935-1948 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Incoming Letters - L, 1941-1952 (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Incoming Letters - Liberal King Mining Co., 1927-1950 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Incoming Letters - M, 1940-1952 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Incoming Letters - Millard, William, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Incoming Letters - N, 1936-1953 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Incoming Letters - P, 1941-1954 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Incoming Letters - R, 1936-1949 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - Incoming Letters - S, 1927-1953 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Incoming Letters - Sunset Minerals Inc., 1949-1954 (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Incoming Letters - T, 1937-1953 (Box-folder 4/26)
  - Incoming Letters - W, 1931-1953 (Box-folder 4/27)
  - Incoming Letters - XYZ, 1938 (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Incoming Letters - Unidentified, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Outgoing Letters, 1927-1954 (Box-folder 4/30)
  - Outgoing Letters, Undated (Box-folder 4/31)
  - General Correspondence, 1927-1936 (Box-folder 4/32)
  - General Correspondence, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 4/33)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1954 (Box-folder 4/34)
- LEGAL CASE FILES, 1927-1965; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/3-3/12)
  - Clancy vs. Loveland, 1966 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Charles S. Green vs. U.S., 1927 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - State vs. Huggin, 1927 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Kahlstrom vs. International Stevedoring Co., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Makah Indian Tribe vs. U.S., 1955-1961 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Makah Indian Tribe vs. U.S., 1955-1961 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Makah Indian Tribe vs. U.S., 1955-1961 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Makah Indian Tribe vs. U.S., 1955-1961 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Makah Indian Tribe vs. U.S., 1955-1961 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Retail Clerks vs. Lamberton, et al, 1948 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Wanamaker vs. Puget Sound Broadcasting Co., Inc., 1956 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Grayson vs. Curtis Publishing, 1965 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - US vs. Teamsters, Local 174 et al, 1957 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Brewster, Frank W. (Deeds), 1955-1959 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Brewster, Frank W. (Appraisal of Property Owned by), 1955-1959 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - City of Hope (Trust), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3/12)
- LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1927-1965; SERIES IV (Box-folder 4/36-4/48, 4/55)
  - Legal Documents, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 4/36)
  - Legal Documents, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 4/37)
  - Legal Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 4/38)
  - Legal Documents, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4/39)
  - Tribunal (American Arbitration Association), 1963 (Box-folder 4/40)
  - Affidavits, Testimonies, Retainer Lists, 1955-1963 (Box-folder 4/41)
  - Agreements, Retainer Lists, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/42)
  - Legal Documents, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/43)
  - Teamster Attorney Newsletters, 1965 (Box-folder 4/44)
  - Teamster Attorney Newsletters, 1965 (Box-folder 4/45)
  - Teamster Attorney Newsletters, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/46)
  - Teamster Attorney Newsletters, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 4/47)
  - Binder of Case Summaries on Community Property, Undated (Box-folder 4/48)
  - Ledger Book, 1905 (Box-folder 4/55)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1916-1965; SERIES V (Box-folder 4/49-4/50)
  - Receipts, Tax Returns, Statements, 1916-1950 (Box-folder 4/49)
  - Travel Finances, Client Receipts, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 4/50)
- MISCELLANEOUS RECORDS, 1927-1965; SERIES VI (Box-folder 4/52-4/54)
  - Miscellany, 1949-1969 (Box-folder 4/52)
  - Ephemera, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 4/53)
  - Weary Walker at Art Exhibit, Undated (Box-folder 4/54)